MASON OUREN

masonouren@gmail.com • 305 E. 34th St, Unit 4B • Austin, TX 78705 • (979) 571-7126

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin Bachelor of Science, Biology, Genetics and Genomics

December 2019

Overall GPA: 4.00

SUMMARY

Motivated Researcher specializing in complex molecular assays, including highly multiplexed PCR/CE kit development and Next Generation Sequencing for liquid biopsy. Mason has 2.5 years of experience engineering plasmids in an academic laboratory, with 1 year of industry experience at Asuragen performing Illumina NGS experiments and developing an upcoming PCR/CE diagnostic assay.

EXPERIENCE

Asuragen - Research Intern; Austin, TX

May 2018 - Present

- Prepare Next Generation Sequencing (NGS) libraries and sequence on Illumina MiSeq for liquid biopsy, advancing grant goals
- Optimize NGS library prep protocol to fulfill grant requirements
- Develop multiplex PCR/CE assay technology for upcoming diagnostic kit, including primer design and troubleshooting
- Plan and execute experiments, generate Capillary Electrophoresis and NGS data, and interpret results for future application
- Ensure reproducibility by maintaining detailed records of experiments in Electronic Laboratory Notebook

Freshman Research Initiative - Peer Mentor and Undergraduate Researcher; Austin, TX

January 2017 - May 2019

- Created novel gene-promoter constructs for cell fate regulation research
- Generated plasmid library and transformed A. thaliana to produce visible phenotype, contributing to peer-reviewed article
- Managed lab by maintaining instruments and training peers in protocols and independent research projects
- Exercised sterile technique to avoid contamination and produce high quality reaction products
- Guided students on assignments and explained fundamental knowledge of molecular biology and its applications in research

Jump! Gymnastics - Coach; Austin, TX

May 2017 - December 2017

- Supervised classes of up to 8 students while simultaneously offering improvements and promoting student safety
- Exhibited thorough knowledge of skill progressions and led student advancement to upper levels
- Engaged with parents to develop relationships and increase trust for further participation in the program

SKILLS

Computer Skills: Genemapper, Geneious (basic), R (basic), Microsoft Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook **Laboratory Skills:** PCR, NGS, CE, Electroporation, Protein Chromatography, Cloning, DNA isolation, Cell Culture, ELISA **Languages:** Intermediate Spanish

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND ACTIVITIES

Ignite Texas - Co-Chair

October 2017 - August 2018, October 2018 - August 2019

- Mentored incoming Longhorns and helped them establish strong relationships and foundations for success
- Planned and managed team meetings for groups of 13 students to train them as camp counselors
- Led camps of 40 incoming freshmen in team building exercises and focused times of learning
- Volunteered 8 hours per week to invest in the lives of fellow students and strengthen the organization

Terry Scholar - Scholarship Recipient and Organization Member

August 2016 - Present

Distinguished College Scholar - Award Recipient

April 2018, April 2019

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Computational Biology and Bioinformatics - Data Wrangling in R

October 2019

- Applied both established and recently developed dplyr functions to combine and manipulate datasets concerning national statistics around the globe
- Performed Principle Component Analysis to reduce data dimensionality and visualize obscure trends in data